Guide to the Department of Athletics, Yale University, Motion Pictures Documenting Men's Crew
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Department of Athletics, Yale University, motion pictures documenting men's crew
1930-1994
RU 968
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
15
(28 motion pictures)
The records consist of 16 mm films and VHS videotapes documenting men's crew races and training at Yale.
Yale University. Dept. of Athletics
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 38-B (YRG 38-B), Records documenting specific sports at Yale.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The materials were transferred from the Department of Athletics, 2004-2007.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Conditions Governing Access
Original motion picture films and videotapes may not be played. Researchers should consult a reference archivist for policies and procedures governing the creation of duplicating masters and use copies of original items.
Arrangement
The materials are arranged by accession.
Scope and Contents
The records consist of 16 mm films and VHS videotapes documenting men's crew races and training at Yale.
There is also film of the Yale-Harvard boat races, circa 1930, with film of the 1930 Yale-Army football game donated by John Kieffer (see RU 971, Accession 2013-A-082).
College athletes; College sports; Rowing; Motion pictures (visual works); Videotapes; Yale University -- Rowing; Yale University -- Sports; Yale University -- Students; Yale University. Dept. of Athletics
- Men's crew films, 1931-1941; Accession 2005-A-113
  - Varsity 150 lb., 1931 May 21; 1 (Box 1)
  - Freshmen 150 lb., 1931 May 21; 1 (Box 2)
  - Varsity 150 lb., 1932 or 1933; 1 (Box 3)
  - At Gales Ferry, 1933; 1 (Box 4)
  - Varsity 150 lb., 1933 April 25; 1 (Box 5)
  - Junior Varsity, 1937 June 10; 1 (Box 6)
  - Freshmen at New London, 1937 March 03; 1 (Box 7)
  - Freshmen?, 1939 October; 1 (Box 8)
  - Freshmen, 1941; 1 (Box 9)
  - Freshmen, 1938 March; 1 (Box 10)
- Men's crew films, 1950-1967; Accession 2008-A-054
  - Marietta Regatta; varsity crew practice, 1950; 1 (Box 1)
  - New London vs. Harvard, 1963; 1 (Box 2)
  - Championship race, Vichy (France), 1967; 1 (Box 3)
- Men's crew videotapes, circa 1930-1994; Accession 2006-A-033
  General
  See also: RU 971, Accession 2013-A-082, box 1 for film of the Yale-Harvard boat races, circa 1930. This is on a reel with film of the 1930 Yale-Army football game, donated by John Kieffer.
  - Yale-Harvard Regatta, undated; 1 (Box 1)
  - Interview with Church Peters crew, undated; 1 (Box 2)
  - 1930's crew, 1; videotape (VHS) (Box 3)
  - Men's crew, 1937-1939 (3 minutes), 1 (Box 4)
  - 1937 crew, 1 (Box 5)
  - Yale-Harvard Regatta (edited ESPN coverage), 1981; 1 (Box 6)
  - Freshman practices, Tampa, 1983; 1 (Box 7)
    - Use copy, 1 (Box 7U)
  - Crew races, 1983; 1 (Box 8)
    Scope and Contents
    Includes MIT, Columbia-Pennsylvania, and Harvard-Yale-Princeton races.
    - Use copy, 1 (Box 8U)
  - Yale crew, France, 1986; 1 (Box 9)
    - use copy, 1 (Box 9U)
  - National Lightweight 8 practice, 1988 July; 1 (Box 10)
    - Use copy, 1 (Box 10U)
  - United States 1989 Lightweight 8 practice with Heavyweight National 8, 1 (Box 11)
    - Use copy, 1 (Box 11U)
  - Alumni row, 1990 October; 1 (Box 11)
  - Early 1989 United States Lightweights, 1 (Box 11)
  - Freshman Lagoon Class of 1989 - Varsity practice skit, circa 1989; 1 (Box 12)
  - National Collegiate Rowing Championship (Location Video Productions, Inc., Cincinnati, Ohio), 1994 June 11; 1 (Box 13U)
  - Varsity, undated; 1 (Box 14)
  - [Unidentified], undated; 1 (Box 15)